<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Visualizing 120 years of Summer Olympics</title>
    <link>https://example.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Visualizing 120 years of Summer Olympics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 15:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://example.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Female Participation in Summer Olympics</title>
      <link>https://example.com/lit/lit-female/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/lit/lit-female/</guid>
      <description>Many attempts have already been made to visualize female participation in the Olympics. The most basic one (Bmallion, 2015) is using tables to display the information about countries with the highest and lowest percentages of female athletes, and to show female percentages across the 120 years of the Olympics. See Table 1.
  Table 1(a): Countries with the highest rate of female participation
    Table 1(b): Female percentage in Olympic events</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Female Participation over Time</title>
      <link>https://example.com/plot/01-plot-female/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/plot/01-plot-female/</guid>
      <description>As planned above, we started with a simple line graph displaying both male and female athletes’ percentage against all athletes. The strength of this method is that it is simple and clear. It shows that the female percentage has been steadily growing in the past century at the Olympics. The drawback is that it does not generate a stark contrast between male and female as a stacked bar chart can do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plans: Female Participation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/plans/01-plan-female/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/plans/01-plan-female/</guid>
      <description>As discussed above, we will use a line graph, stacked bar chart, and area chart to show the overall trend of female participation in the Summer Olympics. For female participation in each individual continent, we will use KDE in a small multiple.
In a line graph, the x-axis will be time and the y-axis the percentage against the total number of participants. We will show both female and male athletes. See Figure 12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Female Participation Across Continents</title>
      <link>https://example.com/plot/01-plot-female-continent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/plot/01-plot-female-continent/</guid>
      <description>To visualize changes in female participation in each continent, we first used a simple line graph where we put all the continent together. The x-axis is time, and the y-axis is female participation. The legend shows the colors associated with the continents. See Figure 25.
  Figure 25: Line graph for female participation by continent
  The graph was very messy. As there were six continents and one global average, we could not distinguish between the seven categories very easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home-field Advantage</title>
      <link>https://example.com/lit/homefiled/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/lit/homefiled/</guid>
      <description>Similar to the attempt at showing female participation, simple and basic tables were utilized to examine the existence of home-field advantage at the Olympics (Pettigrew &amp;amp; Reiche, 2016). See Figure 4.
  Figure 4: Medals won by host countries at host year and the previous Olympics, Pettigrew &amp;amp; Reiche (2016)
  This visualization shows a table comparing the total number of medals earned at the host year and the previous Olympics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plans: Home-field Advantage</title>
      <link>https://example.com/plans/02-plan-homefiled/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/plans/02-plan-homefiled/</guid>
      <description>To examine whether there exists a home-field advantage at the Olympics, we will first use a scatter plot with jitter. The x-axis will be countries that have ever been a host, and the y-axis will be the percentage against the total number of medals a country earned. Each dot represents an Olympic Games the country has participated in. Black dots denote data for a “non-host” year and orange dots denote data for host year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home-field Advantage</title>
      <link>https://example.com/plot/02-plot-homefiled/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/plot/02-plot-homefiled/</guid>
      <description>As discussed above, we first tried scatter plot with jitter. The x-axis is the countries that have ever hosted the Olympics and the y-axis denotes the percentage of medals earned by a country against the total number of medals in that year. Blue dots represent data when the country was not the host and the orange ones for when it was the host. See Figure 30.
 Figure30: Scatter plot with jittering for home-field advantage</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medal Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://example.com/lit/efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/lit/efficiency/</guid>
      <description>The most straightforward way of measuring a country’s efficiency of earning medals is to count the number of medals per athlete participating. This method was used by Pettigrew and Reiche (2016) in their analysis of home-field advantage.
Some scholars argued that when assessing the efficiency of medal production, we need to take into account the resources that countries possess, such as GDP and population. From an economics perspective, Rathke and Woitek (2007) came up with a sophisticated formula calculating this efficiency, and visualized the results using multiple box plots that were stacked horizontally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plan: Medal Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://example.com/plans/03-plan-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/plans/03-plan-efficiency/</guid>
      <description>The index of “medal efficiency” will be calculated as medal points per athlete participating. We will use an interactive choropleth world map to show each participating country and region’s score. See Figure 18.
  Figure 18: Choropleth map for medal efficiency
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medal Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://example.com/plot/03-plot-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/plot/03-plot-efficiency/</guid>
      <description>As planned, first of all, we did data manipulation before plotting. Golds were given 4 points, Silver 2, and Bronze 1. Attendance without any medals was assigned to 0 point. A country’s “medal efficiency” was calculated as the quotient of total medal points and the total number of athletes participating over 120 years. Therefore, if a country / region has a medal efficiency of 0.5, it means that on average, each athlete of that country / region earned half a Bronze.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plans: Ranking Sports</title>
      <link>https://example.com/plans/04-plan-ranking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/plans/04-plan-ranking/</guid>
      <description>First, we will use a bar chart where the x-axis will be the different sports and the y-axis the corresponding number of athletes. See Figure 19.
Second, we will show this ranking using a word cloud in which larger font size denotes a higher number of participants. This graph will be clearer and more direct because viewers can intuitively get a sense of the relative size of participation of a sport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ranking Sports by Number of Athletes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/lit/ranking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/lit/ranking/</guid>
      <description>Dutta (2018) in his Kaggle post visualized the top 10 sports that USA excel by putting 10 boxes vertically with sports winning the most gold medals on top. See Figure 11.
  Figure 11: Ranking of sports by weighted medals
  This visualization is transparent and clear but the problem is that it is limited to only about 10 items, which is not enough for us to visualize all the sports in the Summer Olympics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ranking Sports</title>
      <link>https://example.com/plot/04-plot-ranking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/plot/04-plot-ranking/</guid>
      <description>To rank sports according to the number of athletes, we first plotted a bar chart, each bar representing a category. As can be seen below, since there were too many categories, the names of sports overlapped to a degree that most of them were indistinguishable. Since there are around thirty sports, using colors is not an ideal option.
We then thought about the word cloud. In word clouds, the size of words is associated with the frequencies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>